<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Others on Arsh Siddiqui</title>
    <link>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Others on Arsh Siddiqui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Listens</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/my_listens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/my_listens/</guid>
      <description>My Listens&#xD;#&#xD;This will update every two hours as the music itself that I listen to changes. The data comes from the Spotify API, and was encorporated with Spotipy. Short Term Listens&#xD;#&#xD;These are the songs I have been listening to the most in the past four weeks.&#xA;Medium Term Listens&#xD;#&#xD;These are the songs I have been listening to the most in about the past half year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Websites</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/other_websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/other_websites/</guid>
      <description>Other Websites&#xD;#&#xD;These are some of my older websites that showcase other projects of mine. They&amp;rsquo;re all effectively poorly executed jokes.&#xA;Multiple Deprivation in London&#xA;Showcase multiple deprivation, a measure of poverty, across the different wards of London.&#xA;NYC Buildings v. Heights&#xA;Basic geospatial project, showcasing New York City modeled with building heights.&#xA;Humourous Marketplace&#xA;Made for a hackathon, and I was tired.&#xA;Limbousine&#xA;Takes you to the nearest middle of nowhere from your current location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Articles I Have Read</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/articles/</guid>
      <description>The Best Articles I Have Read&#xD;#&#xD;These are some of the best articles I have read, those that have made me think or feel an emotion more strongly than I am used to. These may be news articles, but are more likely to be phrased in the form of stories. They are organized in terms of publication date.&#xA;2023&#xD;#&#xD;Paul Bowles in Tangier&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how to explain this article.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Short Stories I Have Read</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/shortstories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.pages.dev/others/shortstories/</guid>
      <description>The Best Short Stories I Have Read&#xD;#&#xD;These are some of the best short stories I have read. These have made me feel things I would not normally feel reading stories and think about things more deeply than I would otherwise, or maybe they were just a fun read. They are organized in terms of publication date.&#xA;2023&#xD;#&#xD;The Third Law of Magic&#xA;A story about art, and the difficulty of expression.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
